The ceremony is about to begin.
The Doors is a music, drama, history film directed by Oliver Stone.
The story of the famous and influential 1960s rock band and
its lead singer and composer, Jim Morrison.
Jim Morrison, played by Val Kilmer.
Pamela Courson, played by Meg Ryan.
Ray Manzarek, played by Kyle MacLachlan.
Robby Krieger, played by Frank Whaley.
John Densmore, played by Kevin Dillon.
Paul Rothchild, played by Michael Wincott.
The Doors is a 1991 American biographical musical film directed by
Oliver Stone, who also co-wrote the film with J.
Randall Jahnson.
The film is based on the history of American rock band the Doors
and their influence on music and counterculture.
The film stars Val Kilmer as singer Jim Morrison, Meg Ryan as Morrison's girlfriend Pamela Courson, Kyle MacLachlan as keyboardist Ray Manzarek, Frank Whaley as
lead guitarist Robby Krieger, Kevin Dillon as drummer John Densmore, Billy Idol as Cat, and Kathleen Quinlan as journalist Patricia Kennealy.
The film portrays Morrison as a larger-than-life icon of 1960s rock and roll and counterculture, including portrayals of Morrison's recreational drug use, free love, hippie
lifestyle, alcoholism, interest in hallucinogenic drugs as entheogens, and his growing obsession with death, presented as threads which weave in and out of the film.
Produced by Bill Graham Films, Carolco Pictures, Imagine Entertainment, Ixtlan, and Le Studio Canal+, and released by Tri-Star Pictures
on March 1, 1991, The Doors grossed $34.4 million in the United States and Canada on a $32 million production budget.
The film received mixed reviews from critics; while Kilmer's performance, the supporting cast, the cinematography, the production
design and Stone's directing were praised, criticism was centered on its historical inaccuracy and depiction of Morrison.
The film explores themes of rock 'n' roll, airplane, hippie, joint, poetry.
The tone is emotional.